When working with spreadsheets, there
may be occasions where you need to
work with multiple worksheets and have
that data linked across the worksheets.
You also may need to add hyperlinks that
will jump from one specific worksheet
to another worksheet or even to an
external document or an external website.
So using the sample document
that we've been working with
as you've watched these videos.
I'm now going to show you how
you can link information from one
work sheet to another worksheet.
So the first thing I'm going to do is
this one is still called sheet one.
So what I'm going to do is
I'm going to rename that.
So just double click on it
and I can then delete that.
And I'm going to call this
the sales data worksheet.
So that is now the sales data worksheet.
And I'm going to add another worksheet.
So if I click on the little
plus sign at the bottom.
That brings up a new worksheet.
And in this worksheet, I'm just
going to rename it so I can double
click on it to rename it, or I
can right-click and select rename.
And I'm just going to call
this one, the average sales.
So there's no information
on this worksheet yet.
So I'm going to copy some information
from here, but I'm going to copy it.
And when I paste it into the new
worksheet, it will be linked to this data.
So what I want on this new worksheet
is I want basically the first
columns showing the actual sales, the
monthly sales, not the total sales,
the total income or the target met.
Just the information that relates
to the products, the price and the
sales that were from January to
July, including the average sales.
So I have highlighted
all of that information.
So if I now use the shortcut
Control and C, and I've selected
information, so I've copied that,
and that's now on the clipboard.
If I go to the average sales
worksheet and select cell A1, I
can go to the paste option there.
And then that gives me a range of options,
or I can also right-click in that cell.
And then this gives me
the options for pasting.
And what I'm looking for is I'm
looking for the paste link option.
So it's a little clipboard with
a two chain links together, and
I select that, and that has now
pasted that as a linked object.
And just to make the data more
presentable I can just do the little
triangle and double-click between
two of the columns to make sure that
the data is all clear and visible.
So we'll go back to
that and select escape.
So I've got the information on there.
And as you can see, it mirrors
the information on the average
sales so they're both the same.
And you can tell that it is linked that
if I'm on the average sales and I select
one of the cells, you can see in the
formula bar that it equals sales data,
C2, so it's equalling, and it's looking
on the sales data worksheet, and it's
looking at cell C2 and similarly for the
February sales, sales data, D2 and for the
March sales, for the one hour experience,
sales data E5 and the average sales.
So again, as you can see, all
of the information is linked
to the previous worksheet.
So if anything has changed on here.
So for example, I changed the January
sales for the weekend experience.
And if I look at that now that will
automatically update on the average sales.
So any data that has changed on here,
but only in that area there, if that
information changes, obviously we didn't
copy and paste that because we didn't
want to show that there that won't change.
So for example, it may be a case that
I need a new worksheet and I'm going
to click on another worksheet and this
one here, I'm going to call "income".
And again, there's nothing on there.
And in this one, I'm just going to
demonstrate how I can link information
by selecting non-adjacent columns.
So for the first one, we selected those
columns, which was quite straightforward.
I just clicked in product, held
the mouse down and dragged it along
till I had selected the information.
For this one I need this
information and this information.
So I can't do that
straightforward by doing that.
What I have to do is the first
thing I do is I have to select the
information that I require in these
two columns, which is that, and then
hold down the CTRL key and then I can
go along and select the information
that I require in columns J, K and L.
And again, I can now select copy.
So Control and C.
As you can see, both areas
have been selected and copied.
If I go to income, I can then
right-click into that cell,
paste the link option again.
And as you can see, I'll just widen
the columns a little bit so everything
will be seen, that is still linked.
So that shows you how you can
link data within worksheets, so
this time if you want to have
information on specific worksheets.
So again, if I change the April
sales there to that, obviously
all that information changes,
but it will also change on the
income as well as the average.
As well as linking information on
separate worksheets, it may be a case
that you need to add a hyperlink.
So I may need to add a hyperlink
that will go to -  straight to the
income or the average sales worksheet.
So I can take the text in there, if
I typed in the text average sales,
and I then right-clicked on that.
I can select link at the very bottom.
So if I select link, it will
then ask me what I want to do.
So this is inserting a hyperlink.
So a hyperlink is the same, whether
it's linking between different
worksheets within a spreadsheet,
or whether you're going to actually
link to an external source.
It just means that you have
to select the right option.
So for this instance, I'm going to
select a place in this document.
Now when I select place in this
document, it automatically tells me
which worksheets that I can link to.
So I've typed the text, average sales,
and I'm going to link to the average
sales, select OK, and as you can see, it's
now gone blue so it's like a web link.
If I click on that, it automatically
jumps to the average sales.
So if I click on there and it jumps
to the average sales, and again, if
I go back and I select income, and
then I right click on that and select
link, place in this document, and I
needed to go to the income worksheet.
And then if I open that up and
then click on that, it takes me
straight to the income worksheet.
Obviously we haven't got much data on
the spreadsheet, but if you're working
with multiple worksheets within a
spreadsheet, this can be extremely useful.
As with Word or PowerPoint, you
may also apply hyperlinks to
websites or other documents.
And again, all you would do there
is you would insert some text, so
it could be home page and you could
then right-click on that, select link
and it would be an existing file or
webpage that you would need to select.
So if it's in the document, you
would select place in this document,
or existing file or webpage.
The text to display would be
homepage and then whatever web
address you wanted to put in.
So just as an example, I'll just
type in Google and select OK.
And that is now taking me to Google.
When I click on that and...
go back to the spreadsheet.
So you can add links whether it be
within the workbook or to external sites.